Register of the Frank Upman Papers, 1930-1974
Hoover Institution Archives
Frank Upman Papers,
1930-1974
78030
Upman, Frank, 1905-1976
2 manuscript boxes 0.8 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, memoirs, reports, and printed matter, relating to American politics, the growth of government bureaucracy and welfare programs, and communists in government
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1978.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
United States. Commission on Organization of the Executive Branch of the Government (1953-1955); United States. National Recovery Administration; United States. War Assets Administration; United States. Work Projects Administration; Bureaucracy; Communism; Communism--United States; Public welfare--United States; Subversive activities--United States; United States--Politics and government; United States--Politics and government--20th century; Conservatism
Biographical Note
Frank Upman, 1905-1976
1905 February 13 Born in Washington, D.C.
1924 A.B. (Engineering), University of Virginia
1925-1933 Contractor, consulting airport engineer
1933-1934 Consultant, Assistant Deputy, and later Deputy Administrator, National Recovery Administration in charge of steel fabricating, construction and related codes. Also served as government representative on Code Authorities.
1934-1935 Administrator, State of Nevada, Federal Emergency Relief Administration (FERA) and Work Projects Administration (WPA). Executive Secretary, Nevada State Board of Relief, Work Planning and Pension Control.
1936-1940 Consultant, Work Projects Administration, Washington, D.C.; Regional Engineer, New England area, Work Projects Administration; Chief of Training Program, Foreman Training, New York City; Coordinator of Public and Industrial Relations Activities, Work Projects Administration, New York City.
1940-1941 Acting Administrator, Federal Works Agnecy, Work Projects Administration for Connecticut.
1943-1944 Chief Liaison Officer, President's Committee for Congested Production Areas, Washington, D.C.
1945 Director of Transportation, Allied Control Commission, Italy.
1947-1948 Property and Supply Officer, Office of Administrators, General Review Board, War Assets Administration, Washington, D.C.
1949-1952 Consultant, National Security Resources Board, Executive Office of the President.
1953-1955 Liaison Assistant to the Chairman, Committee on Business Organization of the Department of Defense, Hoover Commission (Commission on Organization of the Executive Branch of the Government.
1955-1964 Executive Secretary, Committee of Hoover Commission Task Force Members.
1976 July 3 Died, Alexandria, Virginia
Series Description
- Memoirs. (Box Box No. 1)
  Unpublished memoirs, entitled FUBAB (Fouled Up Beyond All Belief), 23 chapters in 5 folders. Typescript (carbon copy).
- Correspondence, 1932-1973. (Box Box No. 2)
  Arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent.
- Subject File, 1933-1974. (Box Box No. 2)
  Address list (card files), speeches, charts, correspondence, lists, and printed matter, arranged in alphabetical order by author, subject or title.
- Miscellaneous, 1939-1957. (Box Box No. 2)
  Award (ballot form), conference program and a presentation program. All printed copies.
Container List
- Memoirs
  - FUBAB (Fouled up beyond all belief), 23 chapters in 5 folders, unpublished, typescript, (carbon copy). (Box 1)
- Correspondence, 1932-1973
  - Andrews, George, 1968-1969 (Box 2)
  - Baring, Walter S., 1953-1970
  - Becket, John A., 1961
  - Bennett, Wallace F., 1973
  - Blough, Roger M., 1962
  - Byrd, Harry F., Jr., 1964-1973
  - Cerf, Bennett, 1954
  - Coleman, Henry C., 1972
  - Cropp, Martha, 1970
  - Curtis, Thomas B., 1964
  - Dominick, Peter H., 1973
  - Foreman, Ed, 1964
  - Goldwater, Barry, 1964
  - Hall, Durward G., 1963-1971
  - Hall, Joseph B., 1963-1964
  - Haydn, Hiram, 1956
  - Hook, Charles R., 1954-1956
  - Hurley, Robert A., 1942
  - Irwin, O. W., 1933-1938
  - Irwin, Randall, 1932
  - Johnson, R. W., 1933
  - King, Arthur F., 1954-1968
  - Knowland, William F., 1964, 1972
  - McNeil, Neil, 1957
  - Metz, Kay, 1960
  - Miller, Bernice, 1956
  - Moreel, Ben, 1956-1968
  - Mahoney, Joseph C., 1959, 1961
  - Paul, Willard S., 1962
  - Pirnie, Malcolm, 1954
  - Rarick, John R., 1969
  - Redelius, Julius, 1934
  - Robertson, Reuben B., 1955
  - Rogers, Paul G., 1964-1970
  - Rutledge, Edwin S., 1953
  - Shoemaker, Perry M., 1956-1972
  - Spang, Joseph P., 1962
  - Stewart J. Harold, 1963
  - Thurmond, Strom, 1965
  - Turner, W., Homer, 1963
  - Watson, Albert, 1965
  - Wedemeyer, A. C., 1968
- Subject File, 1933-1974
  - Allied Commission, Headquarters. Transportation Sub-Commission. Condition of UNRRA Supply-Warehouses at Naples.September 4, 1945 (Box 2)
  - Byrd, Harry F., 1958
  - Ford, Gerald R., President, U.S., 1974
  - Hagerty, James C., Press Secretary to the President.
    - The White House.August 12, 1957. Immediate release., Printed copy.
    - Establishing a Career Executive Committee. August 12, 1957. Executive order., Printed copy.
  - Hall, Durward G., 7th District. Missouri. Your Congressman reports from Washington. No. 2, July 15, 1970., Printed copy.
  - Hood. Edwin M., 1963
  - Hook, Charles R., 1955-1963
  - Hoover, Herbert, President, U.S. 1955-1956
  - Hoover Commission Task Force Members, Committee of
    - General, 1954-1964
    - Finances, 1960-1964
    - Findings, 1957
  - Hoover Tower,n.d., Pamphlet., Printed copy.
  - Laird, Melvin R., Secretary of Defense establishes equal opportunity education program in race relations for all members of the Armed Forces,March 5, 1971., Printed copy.
  - O'Mahoney Amendment to H. R. 7665, Defense Department Appropriation Bill for fiscal year ending June 30, 1958. 1957., Printed copy.
  - Rarick, John R., of Louisiana, United Nations Organization Versus U.S.A.: A Case of Reappointment, extention of remarks. U.S. Congressional Record, Vol. 113, No. 21, February 13, 1967., Printed copy.
  - Roosevelt, Franklin D., President, U.S. Inaugural address, March 4, 1933., Printed copy.
  - Theobald, Robert A., The final secret of Pearl Harbor, U.S. News and World Report, April 2, 1954., Printed copy.
  - Truman, Harry S., President, U.S., Executive order No. 10080, September 30, 1949., Printed copy.
  - U.S. Comptroller General. Report to the Joint Economic Committee. Congress of the U.S. Failure to curtail operation at government expense of military commissary stores in Continental United States where adequate commercial facilities are available.April 1964., Printed copy.
  - U.S. Congress. 88th., 1st Session. S. 1093 Bill. To establish a Federal policy concerning the termination, limitation or establishment of business-type operations of the Government which may be conducted in competition with private enterprise, and for other purposes.March 14, 1963., Printed copy.
  - U.S. Department of Defense. Defense Department Appropriations, 1958, U.S. Congressional Record - Senate. July 2, 1957. pp. 9733-9764., Printed copy.
  - War assets administration, September 5, 1946., Printed copy.
  - Westmoreland, General W. C., Address before Joint Session of Congress, April 28, 1967. News Release, Office of Assistant Secretary of Defense (Public Affairs) April 28, 1967., Printed copy.
- Miscellany, 1939-1957
  - National Economic Council. Award to Business Leader, New York City, n.d., Printed copy. (Box 2)
  - USA Work Program (WPA). Presentation of Foremanship Training Certificates, Brooklyn, N.Y., April 17, 1939., Printed copy.
  - Washington Conference, National Citizens' Committee to Curb Inflation, June 24-25, 1957. Program., Printed copy.
  - Unidentified material.